<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DevOpsDerek Blog</title>
    <link>http://devopsderek.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DevOpsDerek Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 23:52:19 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://devopsderek.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Blog</title>
      <link>http://devopsderek.github.io/2020-06-09-my-first-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 23:52:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://devopsderek.github.io/2020-06-09-my-first-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-to-expect&#34;&gt;What to expect&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this should probably be on an about page or the first page of the blog, but I wanted to get my first blog out of the way. This blog will be about a few things that I want to focus on initially, but will likely expand over time, or perhaps get a bit more focussed. I will focus mostly on technology blogs with a sprinkle of the below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DevOps Technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professional Development ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some personal stuff, including my dogs, and my own life experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tips on dealing with stress, impostor syndrome, and how it&amp;rsquo;s affected me through my career.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-am-i&#34;&gt;Who am I?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, my name is Derek Campbell, and I try and go with DevOpsDerek as a &amp;ldquo;personal brand.&amp;rdquo; Sorry, that sounds a little egotistical but we all need to develop one in some way or another. You can find me hanging out on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DevOpsDerek&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and generally, that&amp;rsquo;s the best way to contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a Scottish man based just outside of Glasgow, and I live with my wife and my two chocolate labradors. I like technology, particularly DevOps and Automation technologies. I love quadcopters, dogs, dog walks, reading, football, cars, DIY, and generally just tinkering and learning stuff in my spare time. I do spend a good bit of time on the Sofa as well as watching Netflix, films, and all sorts of documentaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m about as Scottish as it gets, unfortunately, so what that means I am a haggis eating, caber tossing, kilt-wearing, whiskey-drinking aficionado.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-and-motives&#34;&gt;Work and motives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work as a CI/CD Architect at &lt;a href=&#34;https://octopus.com&#34;&gt;Octopus Deploy&lt;/a&gt; as part of the Customer Success team, and I am based just outside of Glasgow, Scotland. I work with some of Octopus&amp;rsquo;s largest customers and also help write content that helps the users of Octopus. This blog holds my own opinions, ideas, and content, and it won&amp;rsquo;t be part of my work at Octopus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to be more of a speaker than a writer, and I&amp;rsquo;ve presented in a few countries and several cities around the UK. I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing about a range of topics freely and may split this over time into multiple websites, but now, it will be on what I mentioned previously. I want to increase my blogging skills over time, and I will likely look back at this first blog and cringe, much like I do when I see old PowerShell scripts I&amp;rsquo;ve written in the past. We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there, no doubt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally I may write about Octopus Deploy and some of the cool things it does, and my aim is only to educate you and also have a place for me to write cool stuff down over time and reflect on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I come from an Ops background and have been doing DevOps before I even knew what it was. DevOps isn&amp;rsquo;t always about being a developer, writing the best code, and it&amp;rsquo;s more about being open, honest, and direct with people while building and fostering a better culture between Development and Operations. I am a big fan of describing DevOps as Dev+Ops, and roles being defined as DEVops for Developers in DevOps, and devOPS for Operation focussed DevOps Engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worked seven years in London, 3 in Melbourne, and a small-time in Singapore, but have also consulted and spoke in a bunch of other countries. I moved back to Scotland a few years back and have never looked back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my career I&amp;rsquo;ve done many things starting in a Help Desk in Glasgow, System Administrator in a technical agency in Hammersmith, a System Architect in a Digital Design agency, Head of Technical Services in Melbourne, DevOps Lead, a Solution Architect and then I moved back to the UK to start my own IT consultancy contracting, and made the jump to Octopus Deploy in 2018 as a CI/CD Architect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;frequency&#34;&gt;Frequency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to aim to write a blog a week, and hopefully more often, and some may be quite long, and others shorter. I may extend this out to vlogging if I can find the time. The quality of the blogs may be higher and lower, depending on what I have on at work and in my personal life. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s ok to have a persona life in technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, you found this educational and happy to get the first blog out of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time, stay safe, love each other and try and be a little more empathetic and kind to other humans.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual Page</title>
      <link>http://devopsderek.github.io/page1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 20:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://devopsderek.github.io/page1/</guid>
      <description>This is an individual page.
 Make a new file in content\page. For example: content\page\mypage.markdown. Add frontmatter, URL can be designated in frontmatter. For example this page has url: &amp;quot;/page1/&amp;quot;.  Alternatively, create the page anywhere inside content and set the type of it to page in frontmatter type: page.    URL of page can be set in the frontmatter with url: &amp;quot;/page1/&amp;quot;. If this URL is not set, page is created at baseURL/page/file-name/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>http://devopsderek.github.io/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://devopsderek.github.io/license/</guid>
      <description>License Page  Copyright (c) 201X [author]
  Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>